Guide to the Louis Durr Print Collection 1513–1835, undated (bulk, 1660s) PR 142
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Leaves from the Theatrum Pictorium, 1660s
  - Engraved by Jan van Troyen (1610–1670)
    - [119] [Lazarus] after Il Pordenone (circa 1484–1539) {110}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
    - [120] [Martha rebukes her vain sister Mary Magdalene] after Francesco Lupicini (1590–1656) {241}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
    - [121] [Lamentation] after Lorenzo Lotto (circa 1480–1556/57) {244}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
    - [122] [Veil of Veronica] after F. Mantua {044}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
    - [123] [St. Sebastian] after Andrea Mantegna (circa 1431–1506) {028}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
    - [124] [Holy Family with St. John] after Palma il Vecchio (circa 1480–1528) {205}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
    - [125] [John the Baptist] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {176}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
    - [126] [Lucretia] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) [or after Titian (circa 1488–1576)] {187}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
    - [127] [John the Baptist] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {172}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
    - [128] [Christ] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {180}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
    - [129] [Daniel in the lions' den] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {175}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
    - [130] [Madonna and Child] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {183}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 13)
    - [131a] [Portrait of a Premonstratensian] after Leandro Bassano (1557–1622) {149}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
    - [131b] [Boy with a flute] after Francesco Bassano the Younger (1549–1592) {150}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
    - [132] [Ascension of Christ] after Jacopo Bassano (circa 1510–1592) {148}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
    - [133] [Saint Margaret and the Dragon] after Raphael (1483–1520) {002}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
    - [134] [Jesus among the Doctors] after Jusepe de Ribera (Lo Spagnoletto) (circa 1591–1652) {141}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
    - [135] [Pluto in his Chariot] after Giulio Romano (circa 1499–1546) {026}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
    - [136] [Salome] after Giovanni Contarini (1549–1605) {039}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
    - [137] [Arrest of Christ / Christ before Pilate] after Andrea Schiavone (circa 1510–1563) {139}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
    - [138] [Frontispiece for the Theatrum Pictorium, a catalog of 246 paintings in the collection of Archduke Leopold Wilhelm of Austria] after David Teniers (1582–1649) {001}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
    - [139] "Christ Crowned with Thorns" [Ecce Homo] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {078}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
    - [140] [Saint with Arrows / Son of the Orator Francesco Filetto] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {081}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 14)
    - [141] [Lucretia] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {084}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15)
    - [142] [Salome with the Head of John the Baptist] after Leonardo da Vinci (1452–1519) {027}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15)
    - [143] [Man of Sorrows / Ecce Homo] after Alessandro Leone Varotari (Il Padovanino) (1588–1649) {238}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15)
  - Engraved by Lucas Vorsterman II (1624–circa 1666)
    - [144] [Judith] after Giorgione (1477–1510) {025}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15)
    - [145a] [Bacchus / Portrait of a man wearing a wreath in a moonlit landscape holding a violin] after Giorgione (1477–1510) {015}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15)
    - [145b] [St John the Evangelist] after Giorgione (1477–1510) {016}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15)
    - [146] [Pala di San Cassiano St. Nicholas] after Giovanni Bellini (circa 1430–1516) {004}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15)
    - [147] [St. Sebastian] after Giovanni Bellini (circa 1430–1516) {009}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15)
    - [148] [Portrait of a man with a book] after Vincenzo Catena (circa 1480–1531) {242}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15)
    - [149a] [Angel] after Palma il Vecchio (circa 1480–1528) {192}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15)
    - [149b] [Angel] after Palma il Vecchio (circa 1480–1528) {193}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15)
    - [150] [Man with book] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {182}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 15)
    - [151] [Saint Peter] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {181}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 16)
    - [152] [Christ carrying the cross meets Veronica] after Jacopo Bassano (circa 1510–1592) {144}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 16)
    - [153a] [The Young David] after Guido Reni (1575–1642) {225}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 16)
    - [153b] [Old Man looking Up] after Guido Reni (1575–1642) {226}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 16)
    - [154] [Penitent St. Peter] after Jusepe de Ribera (Lo Spagnoletto) (circa 1591–1652) {142}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 16)
    - [155] [Madonna and Child with St Louis of Toulouse] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {066}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 16)
    - [156] [Woman with dog and arrow] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {087}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 16)
    - [157] [Seated Venus and her mirror held by Cupid] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {093}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 16)
    - [158] [Portrait of the Orator Francesco Filetto] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {085}, 1660s (Offsite-box 3, Folder 16)
- Series II. Other engravings, 1513–1835, undated
  In Series II, the numbers in [square brackets] preceding each print were assigned by New-York Historical Society staff when the collection was accessioned.
  - [159] "Telemachus Strangling the Lion," after Edward Francis Burney (1760–1848), by William Bromley (1769–1842), 1792, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 16)
  - [160] [Nursing Madonna?] after Titian (circa 1488–1576), by Valentin Lefebvre (circa 1641–circa 1680), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 16)
  - [161] "Portrait de Warin," after Sebastien Bourdon (1616–1671), by Louis Michel Halbou (1730–circa 1809), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [162] "Philip IV of Austria," after Peter Paul Rubens (1577–1640), by G. Hendriex, undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [163] [Men with guns on horseback] by Pieter de Jode (1570–1634), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 17)
  - [164] "Decollazione di S. Giovanni Battista" after H. Stanwick, drawn by Donato Cellesi, engraved by Lorenzo Ruggi (1802–1877?), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [165] "Christine, Queen of Sweden," after Sebastien Bourdon (1616–1671), drawn by Vandenburg, engraved by Pierre Alexandre Tardieu (1756–1844), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [166] "Ferdin: Paer Parmigiano," after Francois Gerard (1770–1837), by Paolo Toschi (1788–1854) and Antonio Isac (1788–1828), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [167] [Man being held over fire] after Peter Paul Rubens (1577–1640), by Lucas Vorsterman II (1624–1667), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 17)
  - [168] "Franciscus Franck", undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 17)
  - [169] [Madonna and child with infant John the Baptist], undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [170] [Jesus walking on water] by Marcantonio Raimondi, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 17)
  - [171] [French royalty and clergy], undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 17)
  - [172] [Madonna and child] by Francesco Albani (1578–1660), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 17)
  - [173] [Woman with long hair holding cross] after Corregio (circa 1489–1534), drawn by Giovita Garavaglia (1790–1835), engraved by Faustino Anderloni (1766–1847), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 17)
  - [174] [Male profile] by Raffaelo Morghen (1761–1833), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 17)
  - [175] "Edward Lord Thurlow, Lord High Chancellor of Great Britain" after Joshua Reynolds (1723–1792), by Francesco Bartolozzi (1727–1815), 1782 (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [176] [Animals] by Nicolaes Berchem (1620–1683), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 17)
  - [177] [Madonna and child] after Raphael (1483–1520), by Pietro Bettelini (1763–1829), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [178] "Giorgio Washington," after Antonio Canova (1757–1822), drawn by Giovanni Tognolli (1786–1862), engraved by Angelo Bertini, undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
    Related Materials
    Same as number 214.
  - [179] "Raffaelo Sanzio," after Raphael (1483–1520), by Vincenzo Biondi, 1826 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 17)
  - [180] [Salome] after Peter Paul Rubens (1577–1640), by Schelte Bolswert (1586–1659), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
  - [181] [Holy Family] by Simone Cantarini (1612–1648), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
  - [182] "St. Martin dividing his cloak," after Anthony van Dyck (1599–1640), drawn by Richard Earlom (1743–1822), engraved by Thomas Chambars (circa 1724–1789), 1766 (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [183] "Galileo Galilei," by Justus Suttermans (1597–1681), by Galgano Cipriani (1775–1857), under Raffaelo Morghen (1761–1833), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
  - [184] [Battle scene] by Cornelis Cort (1533–1578), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [185] "Surge velociter. Et ceciderunt catene de manibus euis," after Domenichino (Domenico Zampieri) (1581–1641), by Domenico Cunego (1726–1803), 1779 (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [186] "Richard Grenville Temple Earl Temple, Viscount and Baron Cobham" after Joshua Reynolds (1723–1792), by William Dickinson (1746–1823), 1778 (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [187] "Gustave Wasa. Dedie a S. M. le Roi des Francais," after Louis Hersent (1777–1860), by H. Dupont, 1831 (Drawer FF-E, Folder 23 (oversize))
  - [188] [Madonna and child] by Albrecht Dürer (1471–1528), 1513 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
  - [189] [Ecce Homo] by Albrecht Durer (1471–1528), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [190] "Martinus Vanden Baugart" (Martin Desjardins), after Hyacinthe Rigaud (1659–1743), by Gerard Edelinck (1640–1707), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [191] "Zacherias," after Michelangelo Buonarroti, (1475–1564), drawn by Jacob Conca, engraved by A. Fabri (?1593?), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 23 (oversize))
  - [192] "Sagra Famiglia," after Benvenuto Tisi da Garofalo (1481–1559), by Lodovico Ferretti, undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 23 (oversize))
  - [193] [Pan] after Pordenone (circa 1483–1539), by Odoardo Fialetti (1573–1638), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
  - [194] [Jesus heals the sick] after Annibale Caracci (1560–1609), by Giovanni Folo (1764–1836), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 23 (oversize))
  - [195] "Salus Infirmorum," after Sassoferrato (1609–1685), drawn by G. B. Borani, engraved by Pietro Folo (1790–1867), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [196] [Jesus healing a cripple] after Lodovico Carracci (1555–1619), by Pietro Fontana (1762–1837), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 23 (oversize))
  - [197] "Sagra Famiglia," after Raphael (1483–1520), by Pietro Fontana (1762–1837), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [198] "Sibylla Cumaea," after Domenichino (Domenico Zampieri) (1581–1641), drawn by Stefano Tofanelli (1752–1812), engraved by P. F. Venetus, 1797 (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [199] "La Maittresse du Titien," after Titian (circa 1488–1576), by Francois Forster (1790–1872), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 21 (oversize))
  - [200] [Holy Family?] by Baptista Fratico Veneto, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
  - [201] "Topbie et sa famille prosternes," after Rembrandt van Rijn (1606–1669), by Johannes Pieter de Frey (1770–1834), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
  - [202] [Salome] after Peter Paul Rubens (1577–1640), by Cornelis Galle (1576–1650), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
  - [203] "Il Temporale del Pussino," after Nicolas Poussin (circa 1594–1665), by Wilhelm Friedrich Gmelin (1760–1820), 1813 (Drawer FF-E, Folder 23 (oversize))
  - [204] "Dr. Herschel," after Frederich Rehberg (1758–1835), by James Godby (before 1790–1820), 1814 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
  - [205] [Two women] after Peter Paul Rubens (1577–1640), by Cl. Goirand, published by T. Valet, undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
  - [206] [The Boy Jesus in the Temple?] after Gerrit van Honthorst (1590–1656), by Carl Hess (1755–1828), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
  - [207] [Women, child, lamb] after Leonardo da Vinci (1452–1519), by Auguste Laugier (1816–after 1880), 1831 (Drawer FF-E, Folder 23 (oversize))
  - [208] "N. Poussin" (self-portrait), after Nicolas Poussin (1594?–1665), by Etienne Frederic Lignon (1779–1833), 1824 (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
  - [209] "Paulus de Vos," after Anthony van Dyck (1599–1641), by Adriaen Lommelin (1637–1673), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 18)
  - [210] [Cattle] by Francesco Londonio (1720–1783), 1763 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 19)
  - [211] [Landscape] by Claude Lorrain (1600–1682), 1651 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 19)
  - [212] "A view of the Ponte–Mole near Rome," after Claude Lorrain (1600–1682), by Thomas Major (1714–1799), 1753 (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
  - [213] "Evrosine, Aglaia, Talia," after Antonio Canova (1757–1822), drawn by Giovanni Tognolli (1786–1862), engraved by Domenico Marchetti (1780–1844), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
  - [214] "Giorgio Washington," after Antonio Canova (1757–1822), drawn by Giovanni Tognolli (1786–1862), engraved by Domenico Marchetti (1780–1844), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
    Same as no. 178.
  - [215] [Baptism of child] by Carlo Moratti (1625–1713), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 19)
  - [216] [Roys Auguste], after Nicholas Mignard (1606–1668), by Antoine Masson (1636–1700), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 23 (oversize))
    Scope and Contents
    L'Honneur quil s'est acquis est sy grand et sy just
    Et l'on aura pour luy tant d'estime et d'Amour
    Que comme les grands Roys prenent le nom d'Auguste
    Les plus fameux heros prendront celuy d'harcour.
  - [217] [Woman with three children] after Corregio (circa 1489–1534), engraved by Raffaelo Morghen (1761–1833), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 19)
  - [218] "Johannes Vulpatus," after Angelica Kauffman (1741–1807), drawn by Stefano Tofanelli (1752–1812), engraved by Raffaelo Morghen (1761–1833), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 19)
  - [219] "Justitia," after Raphael (1483–1520), drawn by Bernardino Nocchi (1741–1812), engraved by Raffaelo Morghen (1761–1833), under Giovanni Volpato (1735–1803), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
  - [220] "Philosophia," after Raphael (1483–1520), drawn by Bernardino Nocchi (1741–1812), engraved by Raffaelo Morghen (1761–1833), under Giovanni Volpato (1735–1803), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
  - [221] "Poesis," after Raphael (1483–1520), drawn by Bernardino Nocchi (1741–1812), engraved by Raffaelo Morghen (1761–1833), under Giovanni Volpato (1735–1803), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
  - [222] "Theologia," after Raphael (1483–1520), drawn by Bernardino Nocchi (1741–1812), engraved by Raffaelo Morghen (1761–1833), under Giovanni Volpato (1735–1803), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
  - [223] "Ego Dormio et cor meum vigilat," after Peter Paul Rubens (1577–1640), drawn by Pietro Angeletti (active 1758–1786), engraved by Raffaelo Morghen (1761–1833), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
  - [224] [Man holding sheet of paper] after Anthony van Dyck (1599–1641), by Robert van Vorst (1597–circa 1635), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 19)
  - [225] "Animus Illabere Nostris," after Peter Paul Rubens (1577–1640), by Paulus Pontius (1603–1658), 1627 (Drawer FF-E, Folder 23 (oversize))
  - [226] "Theodorus Vanlonius," after Anthony van Dyck (1599–1641), by Paulus Pontius (1603–1658), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 19)
  - [227] "Simon de Vos," after Anthony van Dyck (1599–1641), by Paulus Pontius (1603–1658), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 19)
  - [228] [Nativity scene] after Corregio (circa 1489–1534), by Carl Heinrich Rahl (1779–1843), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 23 (oversize))
  - [229] [Popes], undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 19)
  - [230] [Saints], undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 19)
  - [231] [Greek philosophers], undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 20)
  - [232] [Pope and Roman emperors], undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 20)
  - [233] [Man in hat] after Rembrandt van Rijn (1606–1669), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 20)
  - [234] [Castle] by Thomas Wyck (1616–1677), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 20)
  - [235] [Landscape], undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 20)
  - [236] "Henri IV et ses Enfants," after Jean–Auguste–Dominique Ingres (1780–1867), by Theodore Richomme (1785–1849), 1835 (Drawer FF-E, Folder 23 (oversize))
  - [237] [Carrying the cross] after Albrecht Dürer (1471–1528), by Aegidius Sadeler II (circa 1570–1629), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
  - [238] "Helena Forman, Rubens's Second Wife" after Anthony van Dyck (1599–1640), drawn by George Farington (1752–1788), engraved by Louis Sailliar (1748–circa 1795), 1783 (Drawer FF-E, Folder 23 (oversize))
  - [239] "Mucius Scaevola before Porsenna," after Peter Paul Rubens (1577–1640), by Jakob Matthias Schmutzer (1733–1811), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 23 (oversize))
  - [240] "Celebrated Madonna of Coreggio, with the Magdalen, St. Jerom [sic], &c," after Corregio (circa 1489–1534), drawn by Parma, engraved by Robert Strange (1721–1792), 1771 (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
  - [241] [Landscape] by Herman van Swanevelt (1600–1665), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 20)
  - [242] [Pan and angel] after Agostino Carracci (1557–1602), by Flaminio Torri (1621–1661), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 20)
  - [243] [Man with book] after Anthony van Dyck (1599–1641), by Robert van Vorst (1597–circa 1635), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 20)
  - [244] "Nox," after Francesco Barbieri (1623–1698), drawn by Stefano Tofanelli (1752–1812), engraved by Giovanni Volpato (1735–1803), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
  - [245] "Lucifer," after Francesco Barbieri (1623–1698), drawn by Stefano Tofanelli (1752–1812), engraved by Giovanni Volpato (1735–1803), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
  - [246] "Semper Paupers habetis vobiscum me autem non semper habetis," after Paolo Veronese (1528–1588), by Giovanni Volpato (1735–1803), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
  - [247] [Landscape illustrating quote from Virgil] after Claude Lorrain (1604–1682), drawn by Stefano Tofanelli (1752–1812), engraved by Giovanni Volpato (1735–1803), undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 23 (oversize))
    IUNIPERI GRAVIS UMBRA. NOCENT ET FRUGIBUS UMBRAE
    ITE DOMUM SATURAE VENIT HESPERUS ITE CAPELLAE
  - [248] [Woman with flowers in bosom] after Joshua Reynolds (1723–1792), by Thomas Watson (1748–1781), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 20)
  - [249] [The Honourable Mrs. Bou], undated (Drawer FF-E, Folder 23 (oversize))
  - [250] "Louis Phelypeaux Comte de Saint Florentin," after Louis Tocque (1696–1772), by Johann Georg Wille (1715–1808), 1751 (Drawer FF-E, Folder 22 (oversize))
  - [251] "Colbert," by Paolo Toschi (1788–1854), 1811 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 20)
  - [252] "Nicolo Machiavelli," by Santi di Tito (1536–1603), by Paolo Toschi (1788–1854) and Antonio Isac (1788–1828), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 20)